Dear esteemed Dharma friends, regarding the
à Kính thưa các quý đạo hữu nghi thức
49th and 100th-day memorial service for the Dharma community, Tâm Chiếu Hoàn Quán
cúng lễ Tuần thất 49 100 ngày dành cho
is currently
đạo tràng thì tâm chếu hoàn quán đang
finalizing preparations for the
chỉnh sửa soạn nốt về cúng cúng trong
funeral ceremony. We need to
đám ma là trong lễ đám ma chúng ta cần
have the following programs: Firstly, the
có Ngần này Chương trình thứ nhất đó là
preparation program, which we already have;
chương trình chuẩn bị thì chúng ta đã có
we have attendants, ceremonial arrangements, and
ta đã có rồi thị giả rồi lễ sắm hướng
guidance. Today, Tâm Chiếu Hoàn Quán
dẫn thì chúng ta có rồi Thế hôm nay tâm
presents the chanting during the
chếu quán đưa ra cái phần là tụng trong
funeral and the memorial service.
đám ma và tụng trong tuần thất thì tụng
We have two programs for chanting sutras at the funeral: the first for a deceased
kinh trong đám ma chúng ta có hai chương
Buddhist member of the Chrysanthemum Club, and the
là phật tử trong câu lạc bộ cúc và Tức
second for a deceased member who is not a member of the Chrysanthemum Club. Please
cúc vàng và chương trình thứ hai là
understand, esteemed Dharma friends,
cúc vàng các quý đạo hiểu rõ chị
that the program involves chanting sutras
ạ chương trình mà chúng ta tụng kinh
without offering food. We already have the sutras,
không có cúng cơm thì chúng ta đã có bài
but now we will chant sutras and offer food together – that is, we will chant sutras and offer food
nhưng bây giờ là tụng kinh và cúng cơm
to the deceased simultaneously. So,
cúng cơm cho người mất luôn Thế trong
in this program, we
trên trong chương trình này chương trình
call it chanting sutras and offering food at the funeral. Do you
gọi là tụng kinh cúng cơm trong đám ma
understand, esteemed Dharma friends?  The chanting and offering of food
quý Đạ Hữu rõ chư ạ tụng kinh cúng cơm
at the funeral is done after the monks have
trong đám ma là sau khi quý thầy có thể
placed the body in the coffin in the morning. We
nhập quan vào buổi sáng thì chúng ta có
can then chant and offer food to
thể buổi tối đến tụng kinh và cúng cơm
the deceased in the evening, or the monks
cho vong Ninh vào buổi tối hoặc các thầy
can chant in the afternoon, but the coffin will be moved the next afternoon. In that case,
tụng kinh vào buổi chiều nhưng đến chiều
our congregation can come to offer food and chant early in
chúng ta đến Cúng cơm và tụng kinh vào
the morning. Do you understand
buổi sáng sớm các quý Đạo Hữu đã hiểu
the timing, dear fellow devotees? That's the time. Regarding the seven-day
cái thời gian chưa ạ Đấy thời gian vào
memorial service,
đó và cái chương trình cúng tuần thất
we have four
thì chúng ta có bốn chương
programs: The first is for the
trình chương trình thứ nhất là dành cho
congregation performing the seven-day memorial service if
thất dành cho đạo tràng làm tuần
the deceased was a
thất đối với trường hợp người mất là
Buddhist member of the Golden Chrysanthemum Club practicing the
phật tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập tu
Six Harmonies; the
Lục
second is for the
Hòa chương trình thứ hai là dành cho gia
family performing the ceremony themselves if the deceased
đình gia đình tự làm lễ mà người mất lại
was a Buddhist member of the Golden Chrysanthemum Club; the
là phật tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc
third is for the congregation
Vàng chương trình thứ ba là chương trình
performing the seven-day memorial service if
đạo tràng đi làm lễ Tuần thất nhưng
the deceased was not a Buddhist member of the
người mất lại không thuộc phật tử câu
Golden Chrysanthemum
lạc bộ cốc vàng mà là nhân dân phật tử
Club;
khác không thuộc câu lạc bộ cúc
and the fourth is for
vàng và chương trình thứ tư đó là chương
the family performing the ceremony themselves if the
trình gia đình tự làm lễ nhưng mà người
deceased was not a Buddhist member of the
mất thì lại không thuộc phật tử câu lạc
Golden Chrysanthemum Club. So, we have four programs...  Regarding the
bộ Quốc vàng hay chúng ta có bốn chương
reason for dividing the program into four parts, Venerable
trình tại sao lại phân ra bốn chương
Dharma friends,
trình như thế thì Kính thưa quý đạo hữu
when preparing the program,
khi mà soạn chương trình ấy soạn chương
the mind focused on the practice and realized that
trình thì tâm chếu hoàn quán mới thấy là
the Buddhist practitioners in the Golden Chrysanthemum Club are
các phật tử tu trong câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng
truly amazing. The merit
Quả thật quá tuyệt vời cái công đức mà
they have accumulated is immense, Venerable Dharma friends.
họ đã tạo ra rất nhiều các quý đạo hữu ạ
Sometimes, after death, they only have
nhiều Có khi sau khi mất họ chỉ có những
attachments to their families. When the Dharma
cái sở chấp về gia đình thôi thì khi đạo
group provides proper guidance, they will
tràng đến Khai Thị đúng thì người ta sẽ
let go of those attachments and can be
rời xa chỗ chấp đó và người ta có thể
reborn into a peaceful realm because
thác sinh vào cảnh giới an lành vì người
they have created so much merit. Furthermore, our
ta tạo ra quá nhiều công đức và thứ nữa
guidance helps them
là chúng ta đến chúng ta khai thị cho họ
remember the merits they have
để họ nhớ lại những công đức mà họ đã
accumulated. This is extremely important and
tạo lập cái đấy là vô cùng quan trọng và
beneficial for the
Thù Thắng cho người
deceased, Venerable Dharma friends. This can
mất th quý đạo hữu ạ cái đấy có thể làm
enable them to be reborn immediately. And of
cho họ tái sinh ngay lập tức Và tất
course, the program for assisting and supporting the dying also
nhiên chương trình Hộ Niệm trợ niệm cũng
has a similar program, Venerable Dharma friends. It is
có chương trình như thế các quý đạo hữu
for both Buddhist
ạ cũng dành cho những người là phật tử
club members and
câu lạc bộ và cũng dành cho những người
non-members, and a
không phải phật tử câu lạc bộ và lợi ích
great benefit is that we dedicate the
lớn nữa là chúng ta hồi hướng cái công
merit of the Six Harmonious Practices of the entire club to
đức tu tập Lục Hòa của cả câu lạc bộ cho
them.  And the karmic connection is always for them to return to the
họ và tác duyên luôn là cho Họ quay trở
Golden Chrysanthemum Club to practice the
lại câu lạc bộ cúc vàng để thực hành
Bodhisattva path, continuing with the
công hạnh bồ đề tiếp tục với câu lạc bộ
Golden Chrysanthemum Club. That is extremely victorious.
cốc vàng cái điều đó là cực kỳ Thù Thắng
When preparing the program, the Mindfulness Meditation and the Complete Contemplation
khi mà soạn chương trình tâm Chú Hoàn
show that it is truly very respectful to the
quán thấy quả thật là rất là cung kính
Buddhists, very respectful to the
các các phật tử rất cung kính các quý
esteemed fellow practitioners, because the merit created is
đạo hữu ạ vì cái công đức tạo ra là vô
immeasurable and
lượng vô
boundless, so it
biên rất nhiều cho
gives us a
nên cho chúng ta có một cái cuộc chuyển
very wonderful rebirth, a very
sinh rất là tuyệt vời chuyển sinh rất
wonderful rebirth, esteemed fellow practitioners. The Mindfulness Meditation and
tuyệt vời các quý đạo hữu ạ thì tâm
Complete Contemplation also share with you, esteemed fellow
chiếu Hoàn quán cũng chia sẻ với các quý
practitioners, that
đạo hữu thế
if we use the merit of the Six Harmonies,
này nếu như chúng ta dùng công đức Lục
if any Dharma center practices the Six Harmonies well,
Hòa nếu đạo tràng nào Tu Tập Lục Hòa tốt
from the Dharma center leader downwards, without using
từ đạo tràng trưởng trở xuống không dùng
their ego, and practice the
bản ngã của mình mà thực hành tốt cái
Six Harmonies well, then when
việc tu tập Lục Hòa thì khi trong đạo
a family in the Dharma center encounters some strange evil, and
tràng có một gia đình Gặp cái ác lạ nào
those pure people come to
đó mà mà những người thanh tịnh đó đến
practice with a single-minded reliance, the
tu tập với cái tâm nương tựa chuyên nhất
family's karma will change very
thì gia đình người ta chuyển nghiệp rất
quickly. And I would also like to tell you, esteemed fellow
là nhanh và cũng xin thưa với các quý
practitioners, that the Culture and Information Committee has performed a
đạo hữu là ban văn hóa thông tin đã là
miracle, dedicating merit to the mother of
một việc kỳ tích đó là hồi hướng cho mẹ
a Buddhist in the Culture and
một phật tử trong trong ban văn hóa
Information Committee after three days.  Today, there is a
thông tin sau 3 ngày sau ba ngày có sự
transformation that is almost
chuyển hóa gần như là
% amazing, so from the head of the group
% rất tuyệt vời cho nên t đ trng trưởng
to the members of the group, let us
cho tới đạo trảng viên chúng ta hãy tinh
diligently practice the Six Harmonious Principles. The
Nghiêm thực hành các pháp Lục Hòa Lợi
benefits are immediate in this present life, not to mention the
ích ngay trong hiện tại chứ không nói
next. But when
đến là đến kếp sau đâu nhưng mà khi
we, as Buddhists in the group,
chúng ta một phật tử trong đạo tràng
leave our physical bodies and come here, just by being present,
chúng ta bỏ báo thân chúng ta đến chỉ
we
cần có mặt chúng ta chúng ta khai tụng
recite the Enlightenment Sutra, almost striking
xong bài kinh Khai Thị gần như đánh vào
the subconscious of the person. If
cái cái tàng thức của người ta Nếu người
they are attached to something because of anger, delusion, or some evil
ta Vì chấp sân si cái gì đó Vì cái ác
karma, they are clinging to something. When we come, they
nghiệp nào đó mà người ta đang chấp
only
trước chúng ta đến người ta chỉ cần
need us to dedicate the merit of the Six Harmonious Principles
chúng ta cần hồi hướng công đức Lục Hòa
to them, and then we recite the
cho người ta thế thế rồi chúng ta tụng
Enlightenment Sutra. They let go of that attachment and
bài kinh Khai Thị người ta xả cái chấp
fully enjoy the merit
đó người ta hưởng trọn vẹn cái công đức
immediately in this present life. It is extremely beneficial when
ngay trong hiện tại cực kỳ lợi ích khi
the mind is focused on contemplation and preparation. The mind focused on contemplation and
tâm chếu hoàn quán soạn ấy thì tâm chếu
preparation cannot think of this.
hoàn quán không nghĩ ra được điều này
But when the sutra is prepared and
đâu ạ Thế đến lúc mà soạn bài kinh xong
the Enlightenment is done, we realize that
đến Khai Thị thì mình mới thấy ô cái
this Enlightenment part is completely different for
phần Khai Thị này là có những người phật
Buddhists in other clubs and those
tử trong câu lạc bộ khác và những người
outside the club.
ngoài câu lạc bộ khác trên nó hoàn toàn
The mind focused on contemplation and preparation sees it
khác nhau và tâm chiếu Hoàn quán thấy
very clearly.  We are very happy and respectful to all the esteemed Buddhist followers.
rất là hoan hỉ rất là cung kính các quý
Therefore, if you have
kính cho nên nếu các quý phật tử có cha
parents or even children, you should
mẹ thậm chí là con mình nữa cũng nên cho
include them as members of the Golden Chrysanthemum Club.
vào thành viên của câu lạc bộ Quốc và
Just practice and do as you please, and
con con mình cũng nên cho vào vì cứ thực
if your parents are elderly and know about Buddhism, you
mình già rồi nếu biết đến phật pháp cũng
should also include them in the club.
nên cho bố mẹ mình vào câu lạc bộ bảo
We only need to guide them through
mình chỉ cần hướng dẫn cho bố mẹ mình
some of the club's activities and
một số việc của câu lạc bộ cúc vàng và
let them participate freely; that's very
để cho các cụ tùy hỉ thôi cũng rất là
beneficial. Very beneficial indeed! Dear
lợi ích rồi Rất lợi ích nhá Kính thưa
fellow practitioners, after completing the
các quý đạo hữu là sau khi hoàn tất hết
funeral assistance program, along with the
chương trình trợ liệm cộng với Nghi Thức
chanting rituals during the funeral and the 49th and
Tụng kinh trong đám ma và tuần thất 49
100th-day memorial services, the Golden Chrysanthemum Club will print
100 ngày thì câu lạc bộ cúc vàng sẽ in
books. Is that clear, dear fellow practitioners? We will distribute them to
sách các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ inch để
all Buddhist followers in the
phát cho tất cả các phật tử trong câu
Golden Chrysanthemum Club. The introduction
lạc bộ Cúc V vàng thỉnh nhá tâm chếu
will be explained later. The
hoàn quán sẽ giải thích về cái phần lời
introduction
dẫn nhá Phần lời dẫn ạ lời dẫn thì chúng
consists
ta gồm
of four
có bốn
parts: firstly, the section on the Dharma and the practice of cultivating the
phần thứ nhất là phần pháp duyên tu tập
mind.  Read, read, and analyze
tâm Chú Hoàn quán xin đọc và đọc và phân
! Dear fellow practitioners, this is a
ạ Kính thưa quý đạo hữu đây là Pháp hội
spiritual assembly. Only the power of the Dharma can
tâm linh chỉ có năng lực của Pháp mới
help sentient beings in the spiritual realm
giúp cho chúng sinh trong cõi tâm linh
attain enlightenment. Prince Siddhartha attained Buddhahood through the attainment of the Dharma. Therefore, the
ngộ thái tử Tất Đạt Đa nhờ Đắc Pháp mà
Dharma has immense and wondrous power.
thành phật Nên Pháp có năng lực to lớn
For example, if the Buddha
vi Diệu ví như cũng một câu chữ đức Phật
speaks the same words to sentient beings,
nói ra cho chúng sinh nghe thì chúng
they can immediately attain liberation.
sinh có thể chứng Đắc giải thoát ngay
But if
sau khi nghe nhưng cũng với câu chữ đó
we speak the same words to others,
chúng ta nói cho mọi người nghe thì
no one will attain enlightenment. Sometimes,
chẳng có người nào Đắc quả mà đôi khi
we even speak with arrogance,
chúng ta còn dùng tâm ngã mạn mà nói sẽ
causing sentient beings more suffering. Therefore, the
khiến chúng sinh phiền não thêm nên năng
power of the Dharma is the decisive force
lực của Pháp là năng lực quyết định
in this spiritual ceremony. So,
trong buổi lễ tâm linh Vì vậy các phật
Buddhists need to remember that we should only participate in the ceremony when
tử cần nhớ chúng ta chỉ đi làm lễ khi
we have correctly followed the Six Harmonies. When
chúng ta đã đúng với pháp Lục Hòa khi
we have correctly practiced the Six Harmonies,
chúng ta đã thực hành đúng pháp luật hòa
then during the ceremony, the scriptures and
thì trong buổi lễ những câu kinh lời
teachings we recite will, thanks to the
khai thị khi chúng ta đọc ra sẽ nhờ năng
power of the Six Harmonies, enable sentient
lực của Pháp Lục Hòa mà khiến cho các
beings from the human realm to the spiritual realm to
chúng từ cõi người đến cõi tâm linh có
understand, to attain enlightenment, and we ourselves
thể hiểu có thể giác ngộ và chính chúng
may even attain some degree of enlightenment. Right
ta có thể sẽ được giác ngộ phần nào Ngay
in that ceremony, dear fellow practitioners, do you
trong buổi lễ đó đấy các quý Đạo Hữu có
see that we all rely on the
thấy là tất cả chúng ta phải nhờ vào
power of the Dharma?  The power of the Dharma. As for ourselves, we
năng lực của Pháp Còn bản thân chúng ta
have no power at all.
thì không có năng lực gì cả các quý đạo
Do you understand this, dear fellow practitioners? The Buddha had
hữu rõ chỗ này chưa ạ Đức Phật có năng
power because He attained the Dharma. Prince Siddhartha, however,
lực vì Ngài Đắc Pháp Còn thái tử Tất Đạt
had no power. Do you
Đa thì chưa có năng lực gì các quý đạo
agree, dear fellow practitioners? Therefore, the Dharma is
hữu thấy đúng không nhá Cho nên Pháp là
important, and we need the Six
quan trọng mà chúng ta thì phải cần đến
Harmonious Principles. Otherwise, we only
pháp Lục Hòa chứ nếu không chúng ta chỉ
have the Dharma of ego. Because none of us have attained any
có mỗi pháp bản ngã thôi Vì chúng ta đã
enlightenment yet, right, dear fellow practitioners?
ai Đắc quả gì đâu phải không quý đạo hữu
Therefore, we only perform rituals when
cho nên chúng ta chỉ đi làm lễ khi chúng
we have the protection of the Six Harmonious Principles. Only then can
ta có pháp lục hỏa bảo hộ chúng ta chúng
we perform the ritual of mindful contemplation.
ta mới đi làm lễ tâm chiếu Hoàn quán đọc
When participating in a ritual, we are
tiếp khi tham gia khóa lễ là chúng ta
practicing the Bodhisattva path, transmitting the
thực hành công hạnh bồ đề chuyển tải
Buddha's teachings. Therefore, we must transmit the Six
Phật pháp nên chúng ta phải chuyển được
Harmonious Principles to the Dharma assembly so that sentient
pháp Lục Hòa tới pháp hội để cho chúng
beings can connect with the Dharma. If we
sinh kết duyên với Pháp Nếu chúng ta
do not perform the Six Harmonious Principles correctly, we
không làm đúng pháp Lục Hòa thì chúng ta
will transmit the Dharma of ego to the Dharma assembly.
sẽ chuyển cái pháp bản ngã đến pháp hội
This does not benefit
điều này chẳng làm lợi ích cho chúng
sentient beings but creates more karmic obstacles for ourselves.
sinh mà còn tạo thêm nghiệp chướng cho
Do you understand this, dear fellow practitioners?
chính chúng ta C Quý Đạo Hữu có hiểu
Wherever the Buddha went, he was accompanied by the
điều đó không ạ Đức Phật đi đến đâu thì
Dharma of enlightenment. That is,
bằng pháp giác ngộ đến đó tức là ngài
wherever he went, his physical form
giác ngộ ngài đi đến đâu thân Tướng lúc
was that of the seven princes.  Siddhartha,
trước là của thất thái tử Tất Đạt Đa
after attaining enlightenment, became a
phải không sau khi đắc pháp thì thành
Buddha. Therefore, the Buddha goes. That is, the Dharma goes,
Phật cho nên Phật đi Tức là pháp đi thì
only then does the Buddha go. Without the Dharma, one cannot
Phật mới đi còn không có pháp thì chẳng
become a Buddha. So, when we come to this
phải thành Phật cho nên chúng ta đến với
Dharma assembly, it's not that we
Pháp hội không phải chúng ta đến là tôi
come, but we must be certain in our hearts
đến mà chúng ta phải biết chắc trong tâm
that the Dharma of the Six Harmonies has arrived. Do you understand,
chúng ta là pháp Lục Hòa đã đến đây có
dear fellow practitioners? It's not that
quý đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ nhá chứ không phải
I come, but that the Dharma of the Six Harmonies has arrived. I am
tôi đến mà là pháp Lục Hòa đến tôi chẳng
merely the outward form. Just like the
qua chỉ là cái tướng thôi Cũng giống như
Buddha, who had the physical form
đức phật có cái thân tướng là thái tử
of Prince
phần trăm vẫn là thân tướng của Thái tử
Siddhartha before. However, when he became a Buddha, his physical form became much more beautiful, but how much of it remained the physical form of Prince Siddhartha before? Wherever he goes, the
Tất Đạt Đa lúc trước còn ngài đi đến đâu
Dharma goes, not the physical form of
là pháp đi chứ không phải là thân tướng
Prince Siddhartha. We are the same;
Thái tử Tất Đạt Đa chúng ta cũng thế
we are like a material body
chúng ta giống như là một cái vật chất
carrying the Dharma. Do you understand, dear fellow practitioners? Just a
để chở chở pháp các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa
material body. If
ạ Cái thân vật chất thôi ạ Còn nếu chúng
we cannot carry the Dharma, then
ta không chở được pháp thì chúng ta cái
this material body will carry the Dharma of the ego
thân vật chất này sẽ chở pháp bản ngã
to this Dharma assembly, which
đến pháp hội không làm lợi ích gì cho
benefits neither sentient beings nor
chúng sinh cũng chả làm lợi ích gì cho
ourselves. Therefore, the Dharma of the Six Harmonies is extremely
mình cho nên pháp Lục Hòa vô cùng quan
important and central.  Please read
trọ trọng tâm chếu hoàn quán xin đọc
on, Buddhists, before performing
tiếp các phật tử trước khi đi tác lễ
Buddhist rituals, you need to practice the Six Harmonies by
Phật sự cần thực hành pháp Lục Hòa qua
requesting permission from the National Club's Ritual Management Board. This way,
việc bạch thỉnh tại Ban Điều hành nghi
we will have the
lễ câu lạc bộ Quốc và là chúng ta sẽ có
Six Harmonies. Buddhists should not turn themselves
pháp Lục Hòa Phật tử không biến mình
into ritual masters, but clearly understand that this is
thành ông thầy cúng mà rõ biết đây là
a karmic opportunity for them to cultivate the Six Harmonies
một pháp duyên cho mình tu tập pháp Lục
and enhance their spiritual power to
Hòa và Lương năng lực pháp Lục Hòa để
transmit Buddhist teachings to sentient
chuyển tải Phật pháp đến cho chúng sinh
beings. Do you understand, esteemed fellow
các quý đạu Hữu rõ chưa ạ Chứ không biến
practitioners? If we
mình thành ông thầy cúng Nếu chúng ta
do not have the Six Harmonies, what
không có pháp Lục Hòa Chúng ta sẽ trở
benefit would we gain from becoming such a ritual master? The
thành ông thầy cúng như thế trả lợi ích
second part concerns the benefit of the
gì cho mình cả phần hai là lợi ích của
Dharma assembly. Respectfully, esteemed fellow practitioners, as
Pháp hội Kính thưa quý đạo hữu là người
disciples of Buddha, always strive for the benefit of
đệ tử Phật Luôn hướng tới lợi ích cho
yourselves and sentient beings by encouraging and
mình và cho chúng sinh bằng cách sách
supporting each other, sowing seeds of
tấn trợ duyên cho nhau gieo chồng các
goodness to reap the fruits of happiness and peace.
Nhân thiện để được hưởng quả Phúc An Lạc
Regarding spiritual rituals,
đối với các việc cúng lễ tâm linh các
Buddhists should understand the practice methods
phật tử nên tìm hiểu về cách tu tập
in the ritual and the beneficial results
trong đàn lễ và kết quả lợi ích của đàn
of the ritual. That is, we must understand what we are practicing in this ritual and what benefits this ritual will bring
kết quả của cái đàn lễ này sẽ mang lại
to ourselves and others.
lợi ích gì cho mình mang lại lợi ích gì
What benefits does the family bring to
cho gia chủ mang lại lợi ích gì cho
sentient beings? That is, we
chúng sinh tức là chúng ta thực hành
must practice with a clear mindset, esteemed fellow practitioners, do you understand? We
phải có tránh tư duy các quý đạo hữu rõ
shouldn't practice with
chưa ạ Chứ không nên thực hành theo vô
ignorance and lack of understanding.
minh không hiểu biết là chúng ta đến đây
What will be the result of our
lễ cái buổi lễ sẽ có kết quả gì chúng ta
coming here for this ceremony? What is our capacity? First, we
đến đây Với tư cách gì đầu tiên chúng ta
come here to transmit the Six
đến với tư cách là truyển Tải pháp lục
Fires Dharma, esteemed fellow practitioners, do you understand? To create connections
hỏa các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ kết duyên
for sentient beings with the Six Fires Dharma,
cho chúng sinh đối với pháp lục hỏa
we must clearly understand this. Mindfulness and complete contemplation.
chúng ta phải hiểu rõ điều này tâm chiếu
Please continue reading. Firstly, the benefit of
Hoàn quán xin Đọc tiếp một là lợi ích tu
cultivation for the family of the
tập cho gia đình tín
devotee: The family practices cultivating filial piety and righteousness,
chủ gia đình thực hành Tu tâm Hiếu Nghĩa
doing things according to the Buddha's teachings, making offerings to the
làm các việc đúng lời Phật dạy cúng
Three Jewels, dedicating merit to the
dường tam bảo hồi hướng phúc cho người
deceased, bringing benefit to the deceased. The
mất đem đến lợi ích cho người mất đấy
family will practice cultivating
gia đình người ta ta sẽ thực hành được
compassion,
như thế gia đình thực hành Tu tâm từ bi
which means offering food in the ceremony, offering food
đó là hiến cúng vật thực trong đàn lễ
to sentient beings in
cúng thí thực đến cho chúng sinh trong
the realm of hungry ghosts and wandering souls, and saving lives through releasing animals.
cõi ngã quỷ cô hồn và cứu mạng chúng
That is, we know
sinh là Phóng Sinh tức là chúng ta biết
that when we come here, we guide the
rằng đến đấy chúng ta hướng dẫn cho gia
family through this Six Harmonies Dharma, guiding
đình qua Pháp Lục Hòa này hướng dẫn cho
them to cultivate filial piety towards the
gia đình tu tập cái tâm hiếu nghĩa đối
deceased and compassion towards
với người mất tu tập cái tâm từ bi đối
sentient beings.  For the souls and for the
với chúng sinh cô hồn và đối với những
beings that are released, that's
chúng sinh được phóng sinh nhá Đấy gia
how a family practices. The family
đình tu tập được như thế gia đình thực
practices meritorious deeds, achieving enlightenment for themselves and increasing the
hành công đức giác ngộ cho mình và tăng
opportunity for enlightenment for the deceased and for all
duyên giác ngộ cho người mất cho chúng
beings through the ritual of chanting and reciting the Sutra of Enlightenment.
sinh qua việc lễ bái tụng kinh Khai Thị
That is, we come to the family and
tức là chúng ta đến gia đình chúng ta
help them achieve
giúp cho gia đình được thành tựu các cái
these meritorious deeds. We bring the sutras
công đức này tức là chúng ta mang kinh
to the family and chant them together so that the family can
đến cho gia đình cùng tụng để gia đình
attain enlightenment. The
được giác ngộ
family chants the sutras with the hope that the
và gia đình tụng kinh với mong muốn
deceased will also attain enlightenment. That is the merit
người mất được giác ngộ đấy là công đức
the family creates, dear friends, do you understand?
gia đình tạo ra quý Đạ Hữu rõ chưa ạ đấy
And from this connection, the family
và từ cái duyên này mà gia đình được
increases their merit and blessings. When we
tăng thêm cái phần công đức Phước báo
come to help the
cho gia đình nhá mình đến giúp cho gia
family, if someone asks, "Why are you coming to
đình thế ai hỏi là thế các ông đến nhà
my house to perform this ceremony?", we must clearly
tôi làm lễ để làm gì Chúng ta phải Vanh
recite these parts: we
vách đọc ra những cái phần này chúng tôi
help the family with these things, dear friends, do you
giúp gia đình những cái việc này các quý
understand? We must practice
Đạ Hữu rõ chưa ạ Phải tu tập những việc
these things. The second part is the benefit of karma and
này ạ phần thứ hai là lợi ích nhân quả
blessings for the family. We
Phước báo cho gia đình tín chủ chúng ta
must also
cũng phải biết
clearly understand and cultivate gratitude and filial piety. In
rõ tăng trưởng tâm biết ơn Hiếu Nghĩa
many future lives, we will receive care from our parents and
nhiều kiếp về sau được cha mẹ chăm lo
help from others. In the present, we dedicate the merit to our children and grandchildren so that they may receive...
mọi người giúp đỡ Hiện Tại hồi hướng
Being kind and
công đức cho con cháu để được ngoan hiền
virtuous is what we do. When we come to a family,
Ơn Nghĩa đấy chúng ta đến gia đình chúng
we help them, and in doing so, we help
ta giúp gia đình và chúng ta giúp cho
them in a way that creates karmic consequences.
gia đình được cái nhân quả như vậy thứ
Furthermore, in the ritual of offering food to the hungry, we
nữa trong đàn lễ cúng thí thực thì sinh
generate merit, receiving help during times of
ra công đức được người giúp đỡ lúc cơ
hardship and receiving blessings in terms of food and
nhỡ khó khăn được phước phần về đồ ăn
drink. If the family performs this ritual, they
uống đấy gia đình Nếu cúng đàn lễ thí
will receive that merit and
thực thì gia đình sẽ Được cái công đức
blessings. Another benefit
Phước báo đó thứ nữa lợi ích nhân quả
of the release of animals is that it generates merit,
của lễ Phóng Sinh là sinh ra công đức là
eliminating evils such as imprisonment, bondage,
tiêu trừ các ác nạn về giam cầm chói
health problems, illnesses, accidents, and
buộc sức khỏe bệnh tật tai nạn và Thọ
extending lifespan. We help the
mạng được kéo dài đấy chúng ta giúp cho
family with these karmic merits,
gia đình được những cái công đức nhân
and the ritual, performed according to the Buddha's
quả đó và đàn lễ cúng đúng theo lời Phật
teachings, generates good karma and blessings,
dạy sinh ra các công đức Phước báo thiện
increasing happiness for the family in this life and
lành khiến hiện tại gia đình tăng duyên
benefiting future lives. When
hạnh phúc và lợi ích cho các kiếp về sau
we come to a family, we
đấy chúng ta đến gia đình là chúng ta
help them in these ways.
giúp cho gia đình những việc như
And a small third is the benefit for
thế và phần ba nhỏ là lợi ích tu tập của
us Buddhist practitioners in
phật tử chúng ta trong các cái đàn lễ
these rituals: we cultivate compassion and equality, treating the
đó phật tử Tu tâm từ bi bình đẳng Coi
parents and relatives of others who have passed
cha mẹ người thân của người khác đã quá
away as our own, showing
Vãng như cha mẹ người thân của mình
compassion for suffering beings in
thương tưởng chúng sinh đói khổ trong
the realm of hungry ghosts and hungry spirits.  That's why we go there
cõi ngã quỷ cô hồn đấy chúng ta đến đấy
to cultivate that mind, dear fellow practitioners. It's
để tu được cái tâm đó nhá các quý đạo
called cultivating the Supreme Mind.
hữu nhá gọi là là tăng Thượng tâm đấy
We practice the Dharma to cultivate the
chúng ta đi Thực hành pháp để tăng
Supreme
Thượng
Mind through family rituals, offering food to sentient
tâm thông qua đàn lễ của gia đình được
beings in the realm of hungry ghosts and spirits. This is what we
sinh trong cõi ngã quỷ cái này chúng ta
call relieving their suffering. It's still
gọi là cứu khổ cho chúng đây nhá vẫn là
cultivating compassion. Furthermore, we chant scriptures to
tu tâm từ bi đấy ạ thứ nữa là chúng ta
create connections between sentient beings in
tụng kinh kết duyên cho chúng sinh trong
the realm of hungry ghosts and spirits and the Three Jewels, connecting
cõi ngã quỷ cô hồn với tam bảo kết duyên
them with the Six Harmonious Dharmas, the Bodhi
cho chúng sinh đó với Pháp Lục Hòa với
Vows, and the Buddha's teachings
Hạnh Nguyện Bồ Đề với lời Đức Phật dạy
through the scriptures chanted during the
thông qua các bài kinh tụng trong khóa
ceremony. We go to perform the Dharma to create
lễ đấy chúng ta đến đi để làm pháp kết
connections for sentient beings, dear fellow practitioners.
duyên cho chúng sinh các quý đạo hữu ạ
All the above merits are the conditions that
tất cả các công đức trên là nhân duyên
allow sentient beings in the realm of hungry
hội đủ để cho các chúng sinh trong cõi
ghosts and spirits to have a connection with the
ngạ quỷ vong linh cô hồn có duyên với
ritual, to be connected with the Dharma assembly, to practice the
đàn lễ được kết duyên với Pháp hội tu
Six Harmonious Dharmas. This is the condition
tập sáu Pháp Hòa kính đó là nhân duyên
for them to practice the Buddha Dharma, the
cho chúng tu theo Phật Pháp là nhân
condition for them to cultivate and seek supreme enlightenment
duyên cho chúng tu hành cầu vô thượng bồ
in future lives.
đề trong các kiếp vị lai
These actions are part of the
sau các việc làm này thuộc công hạnh bồ
Bodhi practice, aiming for Buddhahood above and saving
đề trên cầu thành Phật dưới độ chúng
sentient beings below, spreading the Buddha Dharma
sinh đó là chuyển tải Phật pháp rộng
throughout the world. That is, we go.  The
khắp thế gian tức là chúng ta đi Thực
practices in these rituals are the
hành trong các đàn lễ này là chúng ta
practice of Bodhi virtues, do you
đang thực hành công hạnh bồ đề các quý
understand, esteemed fellow practitioners? Part three is
đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ phần ba lớn là các vấn
about spiritual matters. First, before performing the spiritual
đề về tâm linh thứ nhất là trước khi làm
contemplation and practice, before
lễ quán chiếu tu tập tâm linh trước khi
receiving this responsibility, we must contemplate
được nhận phận sự này chúng ta phải quán
non-self, which is also called contemplating the Dharma. In the Sutra of Compassionate Water and the
vô ngã giọ là quán Pháp đấy ạ trong kinh
Dharma, Master Ngo Dat Quoc Su
từ bi thủy xám pháp ngài ngộ Đạt Quốc Sư
was offered a sandalwood throne by the king
được vua cúng dường cho Tòa trầm hương
to sit and preach. He developed a sense of arrogance about
để ngồi thuyết pháp Ngài khởi tâm ngã
[music].
[âm nhạc]
This arrogance
ta niệm Tâm Khởi ngã Mạn này được sinh
arose from clinging to the merit of preaching and the title of
ra từ việc chấp Công thuyết pháp chấp
National Master. He thought, "I am
danh Quốc Sư Ngài khởi tâm rằng ta xứng
worthy of being offered a sandalwood throne to
đáng được cúng dường tòa trầm hương để
sit and preach," and
ngồi thuyết pháp và khởi tâm ngã mạn về
thus developed an arrogant feeling about himself. Respectfully, esteemed fellow practitioners, here,
ta như vậy Kính thưa quý Đạo Hữu ở đây
the mind is focused on the complete contemplation. Let me explain the difference between "
tâm chiếu Hoàn quán Xin giải thích cái
I" and "mine." We often say "I,"
về ta và cái của ta chúng ta vẫn nói là
which is a designation for everyone to
tôi đó là danh xưng để cho mọi người
distinguish. The
phân biệt còn cái ngã ta ấy Cái ta xuất
ego appears when we cling to
hiện cái ngã là khi chúng ta chấp công
merit and fame; clinging to merit and fame, the ego appears. The designation "
danh chấp công chấp danh thì cái ngã ta
I," "you,"
xuất hiện còn cái danh xưng là tôi anh
or "sister" is not yet clinging to the ego, do you understand, esteemed fellow
chị thì nó chưa phải là chấp ngã các quý
practitioners? Clinging to the ego is clinging to the
Đạ Hữu rõ chưa ạ Chấp Ngã là chấp những
merits that we have accomplished.  Having done it and accepting that the
cái công mà mình đã làm và chấp có cái
merit exists, accepting that the ego exists, the
công đó hiện hữu chấp có cái tôi đó hiện
mind's reflection, the perfect contemplation, says, for example, that
hữu tâm chiếu Hoàn quán nói ví dụ pháp
this Dharma realm is selfless. For example, a
giới này là vô ngã ví dụ một cái buổi
ceremony performed by Buddhist devotees has
làm lễ của các quý phật tử đó là có rất
many causes and conditions: the
nhiều nhân
cause of the person who composed it for
duyên nhân duyên của người soạn ra cho
the devotees to read; the cause of the Three Jewels
các quý đạo hữu đọc nhân duyên của tam
appearing, which made it possible to compose
bảo xuất hiện mới có được cái sự Soạn
this sutra; the cause of the Buddhas
văn kinh này nhân duyên của chư Phật
attaining Buddhahood, which gave rise to the Dharma; the cause of the holy
thành Phật Mới có pháp nhân duyên của
monks practicing, which
các bậc thánh tăng tu hành mới duy trì
maintained the Dharma; the cause of the patriarchs breaking the karmic ties, which
được Pháp phá nhân duyên của chư tổ sư
continued the lineage of the Dharma to this
đã nối nối dõi dòng giống pháp đến bây
day; the cause of the entire
giờ cho chúng ta nhân duyên của cả đạo
Dharma assembly practicing; the cause of the
tràng tu tập nhân duyên của sư phụ cùng
master and the great Sangha practicing; the cause of the benefactors,
đại tăng tu tập nhân duyên từ sư phụ đại
thanks to many
tăng tu tập mới có thí chủ nhờ nhiều
causes and conditions, we are here. It is just
nhân duyên đó chúng ta mới đến chỉ là
one cause and condition in the countless causes and
một nhân duyên trong Hằng Hà vô số nhân
conditions of reciting the sutra in the ceremony,
duyên để tụng bài kinh trong buổi lễ
but we accept that "I have sown the karmic seed
nhưng chúng ta lại chấp rằng tôi đã gieo
for that family," meaning we have an
Duyên được cho gia đình đó tức là có cái
ego and do all that work, which is only
tôi và bao làm tất cả cái việc đó là chỉ
one cause and condition, that is self-attachment. The
có một duyên thôi đó là chấp ngã còn cái
selflessness, on the other hand, is created by countless causes and conditions,
vô ngã là vô số nhân duyên mới tạo thành
so there is nothing called "
một việc cho nên không có cái gì gọi là
I" here.  Dear fellow practitioners, do you understand? The
tôi ở chỗ này có quý đạo hữu rõ chưa cái
self is the ego, the only thing that
tôi là cái ngã là duy nhất một nhân
can be accomplished by a single cause and effect. The ego is
duyên có thể làm được ấy duy nhất Ngã là
unique, do you understand? This is the
duy nhất mà các quý đ Hữu rõ chưa Đây là
non-self realm; this Dharma realm is a realm where everything arises
vô ngã pháp giới này là pháp giới tất cả
from causes and conditions and
đều do nhân duyên mà thành do nhân duyên
ceases from causes and conditions. There is no such thing as a self. The
mà diệt chứ không phải có một cái ngã ta
term "I" is different from
nào cả Còn cái danh xưng tôi nó khác với
the ego. If you
cái ngã nhá chứ nói là nếu như các quý
understand that,
đạo hữu hiểu rằng là thôi cứ Xưng tôi nó
from tomorrow onwards, you don't know what to call yourself
là ngã Thôi từ mai không biết gọi mình
anymore. You don't know. You don't know how to go out into
là cái gì nữa Không biết Không biết ra
society and talk anymore. Do you
xã hội để nói chuyện thế nào nữa quý Đạ
understand? The attachment to the ego is what is called "
hiểu rõ chưa ạ Cái chấp ngã mới gọi là
I" and "mine," meaning "
tôi và cái của tôi tức là
I have done the ceremony, the ceremony is
tôi đã làm được cái buổi lễ là thành
successful, the ceremony is mine."
công cái buổi lễ là cái của tôi các quý
Do you understand? But "I am the one who did it,"
Đạ Hữu rõ chưa Còn tôi là người làm thì
that's incorrect. A
cái Cái đấy là không đúng rồi một buổi
ceremony has many causes and conditions to be
lễ này có bao nhiêu nhân duyên mới thành
successful, so it cannot be done by "I." Do you understand?
công cho nên không có tôi làm được cái
If you
buổi lễ này các quý Đạ Hữu rõ chưa ạ Nếu
cling to the idea that "I can do it," that's called attachment to the ego. For
chấp tôi làm được thì gọi là chấp ngã ví
example, the mind's reflection on the complete contemplation, sharing the Dharma
dụ tâm chiếu Hoàn quán có chia sẻ pháp
with you fellow practitioners, is also due to the generosity of
với quý đạo hữu cũng là do bố thí của
many people.  The robe worn by the mind, Uncle
rất nhiều người lên cái áo mặc tâm Chú
Hoan Quan, is there no such thing as "I" in the Dharma
Hoàn quán có đâu đúng
teachings, right? Then, from the gratitude for the teachings of the masters, right?
không Rồi từ công ơn thầy tổ dạy dỗ phải
Eating
không đ ăn hàng
daily, right? There are so many, so many
ngày đúng không rất rất rất rất nhiều
causes and conditions, that's why I say there is
nhân duyên cho nên mới nói là không có
no "I," no "I" in the
Không có một cái tôi nào cả Không có một
Dharma teachings. It's all about the convergence of causes and conditions, sharing. And there's the form and name, saying "I am here." Ms. Yen is sitting here talking to you all, but people usually attain enlightenment. There is
cả thuộc về cái ngã nào cả các quý đạo
no "I," no "self," no "merit" belonging to any "self." Do you all understand? That means there is no "I" and
hữu rõ chưa Tức là không có cái tôi và
no "mine" existing; it's the
không có cái của tôi hiện hữu mà nó là
convergence of causes and conditions. When causes and conditions converge, then they disperse,
nhân duyên hội tụ có nhân duyên hội tụ
then they
rồi nhân duyên tán nhân duyên Tụ các quý
gather again. Do you all understand? That's what we must understand correctly, not as a name. If we don't understand it correctly, and we interpret it according to names, we will become confused. The mind of Hoan Quan wants to share this
nha tâm chiếu Hoàn quán muốn chia sẻ với
clearly with you all so that you can contemplate
các quý đạo hữu rõ như thế để cho quý
before
đạo hữu chúng ta quán trước khi khi đi
performing the ceremony: there is no "I," no "mine,"
làm lễ không có cái tôi không có cái của
no "self," and no "mine."  That's
tôi không có cái ngã ta và không có cái
it, so we can
của ta nha đấy rõ như thế để chúng ta
achieve this Dharma, which is called the contemplation of non-
thành tựu được pháp đấy gọi là quán vô
self in Buddhism. With
ngã ở trong Phật pháp
such a contemplative mindset, we generate immeasurable merit, a great deal of
như thế chúng ta sinh ra công đức vô
merit. That is, if we don't
lượng rất nhiều công đức Tức là không
cling to "I," we won't enter the cycle of reincarnation, dear fellow
chấp tôi thì không vào luân hồi các quý
practitioners. If we cling to "I" and "self," we will still
đạo hữu ạ Còn chấp tôi còn chấp ngã thì
enter the cycle of suffering. Therefore,
còn vào luân hồi đau khổ cho nên cái
this contemplation of non-self is called Supreme
quán Pháp vô ngã này người ta gọi là
Wisdom. That's
Thắng Trí Đấy các quý đạo hữu ạ Không
not an ordinary matter, dear fellow practitioners. So,
phải chuyện tầm thường đâu cho nên tất
when we do anything, we should never
cả chúng ta khi làm việc gì cũng đừng
cling to the self, because without clinging to the self, there is
bao giờ chấp ngã vì không chấp ngã thì
no self. We are one of countless
không có ngã mạ mình là một trong vô số
causes and conditions, so what is there to be arrogant about? There is
nhân duyên thì có gì mà ngã mạn phải
no "I," so there is no self, and there is no
không có ta đâu mà ng có ngã và có được
clinging to "I," so there is no arrogance. Without
cái chấp ta đâu mà có ngã mạn nhá Không
clinging to "I," there is no arrogance.
có chấp ta cho nên không có ngã mạn được
The mind is focused on contemplation. Please continue reading. Because the
tâm chếu quàn quán xin đọc tiếp ạ Vì
mind begins to be arrogant about "I," it
Khởi Tâm ngã mạn về ta như vậy nên đã
creates...  The karmic connection between
tạo thành nhân duyên cho oan gia cháy
the vengeful spirit of Little Rabbit and the vengeful ghost transformed
chủ là Vong hồn Tiều Thố báo oán biến
into a human-faced scab on
thành chiếc mụn ghẻ hình mặt người trên
the knee of Master Ngo Dat, causing him
đầu gối chân của ngài ngộ Đạt làm ngài
excruciating pain and making him fall from his incense-burning platform.
ngộ Đạt đau đớn khủng khiếp rớt khỏi tòa
Later, Master Ngo Dat
Trầm Hương thuyết pháp và về sau ngài
had to seek the Dharma for repentance and was
phải Lương nhờ pháp sám hối và được bồ
saved by a Bodhisattva. The vengeful ghost of Little Rabbit
tát cứu giúp vong hồn tiểu Thố báo oán
was because in nine previous lives,
ngài ngộ Đạt là do Chín Kiếp về trước
Master Ngo Dat was an official who unjustly executed Little
ngài ngộ Đạt là quan đã xử oan chém đầu
Rabbit. Therefore, in this life, when Master Ngo Dat harbored arrogance, Little
tiểu Thố nên kiếp này khi ngài ngộ Đạt
Rabbit's ghost had the karmic connection to take revenge on him.
Khởi Tâm ngã mạn nên vong hồn tiểu Thố
So, if we perform a
Đạt Cho nên nếu chúng ta đi làm một buổi
ceremony without contemplating
lễ Nếu chúng ta mà không quán chiếu về
non-self and harboring arrogance,
vô ngã Khởi Tâm ngã mạn thì ngay lập tức
our vengeful spirit from many
oan gia cháy chủ của chúng ta từ nhiều
lifetimes will immediately come to take revenge. Do you
kiếp nó sông đến nó báo thù chúng ta các
see this, dear fellow practitioners? That's
quý đạo hữu thấy có hay không ạ
why we should both contemplate the Dharma to increase our wisdom and
đó cho nên chúng ta vừa quán pháp tăng
transform our karmic forces. Transforming karmic forces
hóa được nghiệp lực nhá chuyển hóa được
to avoid arrogance is important.
nghiệp lực để tránh tâm ngã mạn phật tử
Before performing a ceremony, Buddhist practitioners need to contemplate and
trước khi đang làm lễ Cần tư duy kiểm
examine events to abide in the mindfulness of
tra các sự các việc để an trú trong niệm
non-self through three factors: the following karmic connection: firstly,
vô ngã qua ba yếu tố Duyên hợp sau một
doing things according to the Buddha's teachings, due to merit.
là việc làm đúng lời Phật dạy do công
The merit of the monks' practice in this Dharma assembly is
đức tu tập của chư tăng Pháp hội này có
due to the karmic connection with the Three
được là do duyên của tam bảo của Chư
Jewels and the Sangha. It is thanks to the karmic connection with the Three Jewels and the Sangha
tăng mà có nhờ duyên của tam bảo của Chư
that we have the opportunity to cultivate
tăng mà mình mới có duyên tu tập công
this merit. Therefore, there is nothing that is "I" or "mine."
đức này nên chẳng có gì là ta là của ta
The mind's illumination and the complete contemplation have guided you all
đấy tâm chiếu Hoàn quán đã hướng dẫn các
very clearly, so regarding
quý đạo hữu rất rõ rồi cho nên về phần
this guidance, we must memorize it thoroughly
hướng dẫn này chúng ta phải học thuộc
before
làm lòng các quý đạo hữu ạ rồi mới đi
performing the ceremony. Don't perform the ceremony like a
làm lễ Chứ đừng đi làm lễ như ông thầy
shaman. Secondly, this practice ritual has
cúng nhé hai là nghi thức tu tập này đã
been compiled according to the Buddha's teachings,
được soạn ra theo lời Đức Phật dạy do
compiled by others according to
người khác khác biên soạn theo nghi lễ
Buddhist rituals. Through this, we accumulate
phật giáo nhờ đó mình Tích tập được công
merit and transmit the Dharma, so there is nothing that is "
đức chuyển tải Phật pháp nên chẳng có gì
I" or "mine." These are the two causes.
là ta là của ta Đấy là hai nhân duyên
The third cause is the karmic connection that
nhân duyên thứ ba ba là nhân duyên có
this Dharma assembly has, which is due to the merit of practicing the Six Harmonies
pháp hội này là do công đức tu tập Lục
by the Buddhists in the club, created by the
Hòa của các phật tử trong câu lạc bộ do
Buddhists in the
các phật tử trong ban cán sự câu lạc bộ
club's leadership committee. This karmic connection allows us to fulfill our duties
đạo tràng mới tạo Duyên này cho mình làm
so that we can
phận sự để cho mình có được công đức Lục
accumulate merit,
Hòa để cho mình Tích tập các công đức
rely on it, and practice obedience. Therefore, there is
nương tựa và hạnh Vâng nời nên chẳng có
nothing that is "I" or "mine." Have you all
gì là ta là của ta các quý Đạo Hữu đã
understood?
thông chưa
That is...  Before performing the ceremony, we must have already
ạ Đấy là trước khi đi làm lễ chúng ta đã
contemplated in this way, dear fellow
phải quán trí như thế rồi đấy các quý
practitioners. Therefore, the
đạo hữu ạ Cho nên đạo tràng câu lạc bộ
Golden Chrysanthemum Club is a place for cultivating wisdom, cultivating the mind,
cúc vàng là đạo tràng tăng trưởng trí
increasing wisdom, increasing the mind,
tăng trưởng Tâm Tăng thượng trí tăng
increasing the realm.
Thượng Tâm Tăng thượng giới
While performing the Buddhist ceremony, we need to maintain a
nhá trong khi làm lễ Phật t cần giữ tâm
pure mind, not harboring the intention to
thanh tịnh không Khởi Tâm mình độ được
help the deceased, so we should focus on the
cho vong Ninh nên An chú trong niệm
Three Jewels and the Six Harmonious Dharma,
nương tựa tam bảo nương tựa pháp Lục Hòa
hoping that the deceased will find refuge in the Three Jewels and the Six
mong vong Ninh được nương tựa tam bảo
Harmonious Dharma.
nương tựa pháp Lục
After the ceremony, we should cultivate
Hòa sau khi làm lễ khởi tâm biết
gratitude, relying
ơn Nương Đức tu hành Phạm Hạnh của Chư
on the virtuous practice of the
tăng Nương vào sự tu tập Lục Hòa của các
monks, relying on the Six Harmonious practice of the Buddhists in the club,
phật tử trong câu lạc bộ mà mình được
which
hồn được lợi ích nhờ đức của Chư tăng mà
allows us to perform meritorious deeds. Through the merit of the monks, relying on the power of the Six Harmonious Dharma, all beings, ghosts, spirits, and wandering souls benefit. Through the virtue of the monks, we
mình được thực hành pháp Lục Hòa mình
accumulate merit, which benefits
Tích tập được các công đức khiến cho
ourselves, our families, and all sentient beings,
mình và gia đình cùng chúng sinh được
transforming suffering and gradually leading to happiness.
lợi ích chuyển hóa khổ đau dần được hạnh
That is, after we
phúc tức là sau khi chúng ta thực hành
complete the ceremony, we know
xong ở trong các đàn lễ chúng ta biết
where this merit comes from, so we must cultivate
đâu cho nên chúng ta phải Khởi Tâm biết
gratitude. That is from the beginning.  Before, during,
ơn Thế là từ đầu đến trước khi trong khi
and after we maintain a
và sau khi chúng ta giữ được tâm trí
pure mind, if we haven't maintained a pure mind,
thanh tịnh chưa giữ được tâm trí thanh
that's the practice, dear fellow practitioners.
tịnh đó là pháp tu đấy các quý đạo hữu ạ
Contemplating and practicing correctly as
quán chiếu và thực hành đúng như hướng
instructed above brings the following benefits: Gaining the merit of the
dẫn trên có các lợi ích sau đây có được
Paramita of Giving, benefiting
công đức bố thí ba la mật làm lợi ích
sentient beings; gaining the merit of the Dharma of Non-attachment
chúng sinh có được công đức Pháp Vô nậu
through contemplation and practice of selflessness and the Six Harmonies;
nhờ quán chiếu thực hành vô ngã Lục Hòa
not being followed by spirits from rituals;
không bị vong linh theo về từ các đàn lễ
helping spirits connect with the Dharma of the
giúp cho vong linh kết duyên với Pháp
Buddha; selflessness, the Six Harmonies, and the Paramita of Giving,
Phật vô ngã Lục Hòa bố thí ba la mật lợi
benefiting both the living and the dead. Part
ích cho người sống và người chết phần
four is a
bốn là phần lưu
note: Buddhist practitioners often
ý lưu ý phật tử chúng ta rất hay mắc
encounter these issues. I have
phải một số vấn đề này điều này tâm
heard this before.
chiếu Hoàn quán đã được nghe được rồi
Someone said, "
đấy có người nói này này mà phật tử của
But at funeral ceremonies, the monks
mình thì trong buổi lễ đám ma thì các
perform the rituals, and we also perform the rituals. The monks perform purification rituals, and we also perform purification rituals. What's the
thầy cũng làm lễ và mình cũng làm lễ các
difference?" Truly, this is ignorance, great
khác gì nhau đâu Quả thật là vô minh rất
ignorance, dear fellow practitioners. And I must say,
vô minh các quý đạo hữu mà phải nói là
if we don't repent, we will fall into
câu nói đó nếu không sám hối thì xa
depravity, it's not a normal thing. Please
đọa xa đọa đấy chứ không phải chuyện
continue reading, dear fellow practitioners.  When performing rituals,
đọc tiếp ạ đôi khi phật tử đi làm lễ
clinging to the ceremony and the words gives rise to
chấp vào nghi lễ chấp vào văn từ sinh ra
forgetfulness. One might think, "I'm good at performing rituals, I
thất niệm nghĩ mình giỏi làm lễ được
don't need the monks," or "I perform the ceremony as well
không cần Chư tăng Hoặc mình làm lễ cũng
as the monks," or "I perform it better than the
như Chư tăng hoặc mình làm lễ hay hơn
monks." Such a thought leads to a decline in the practice of taking refuge in the Three Jewels, maintaining reverence throughout one's life, and focusing wholeheartedly on merit. This ensures that after death one will not fall into the three evil paths, except for those who commit grave sins such as killing their father, mother, or an
nghịch như giết cha giết mẹ giết A la
Arhat, causing the Buddha's body to bleed, or disrupting the harmony of the
hán làm thân Phật chảy máu phá hòa hợp
Sangha. That's how the Buddha was. Anyone who maintains such a single, unwavering thought of taking refuge will, by their merit alone, not fall into the three evil paths after death. Yet, we Buddhists often think, "I am better than the monks,
Chư tăng giỏi chứ t chúng ta Khởi niệm
I recite better than the monks," or "I am better than the monks."
lên là mình Chư tăng mình tụng hay hơn
This means
Chư tăng giỏi hơn Chư tăng như vậy là
we have lost the intention of taking refuge, dear fellow
mình đã mất mất cái niệm quy y rồi các
practitioners. Having lost the intention of taking refuge, we need to
quý đạo hữu ạ mất mất niệm quy y rồi cần
go back and repent, dear fellow practitioners,
phải đi Quy lại sám hối các quý đạo hữu
because that is where we have support in the Sangha. The
vì cái đó mình có lương tựa tăng Đâu
intention is that we perform better, that everyone
Khởi Ý là mình làm hay hơn mọi người
likes it more than the monks, that we have lost the refuge in the
thích hơn là Chư tăng làm hay hơn mất
Three Jewels.  The ego is always present, and
luôn quy y Tam Bảo luôn mà bản ngã hiện
karma will follow, dear fellow
tiền luôn nghiệp báo sẽ theo sau nh các
practitioners. Therefore, we must
quý đạo hữu nhá cho nên chúng ta phải
remember this clearly. (
nhớ rõ điều
Please continue reading.) So,
đó tâm chếu hoàn quán xin đọc tiếp ạ Vậy
Buddhists need to know the following:
nên phật tử cần biết rõ các điều sau
Only by creating merit and making offerings to the Three Jewels (Buddha,
biết rõ chỉ có tạo Phúc cúng dường tam
Dharma, Sangha) and the Sangha (community of virtuous conduct) can merit be
bảo C C dường tới tăng đoàn Phạm Hạnh từ
generated from the Sangha's practice and dedication of
sinh ra phúc báo và Hồi Hướng phúc báo
that merit to the deceased, bringing
đó đến cho người mất thì mới đem lại lợi
benefit to the deceased and their families. That is,
ích cho người mất và gia đình tức là
we are the ones chanting scriptures and sowing seeds of
chúng ta là người đi tụng kinh gieo
merit for the deceased and sentient beings. But
duyên cho vong linh cho chúng sinh nhưng
if we want sentient beings to increase their
nếu như muốn chúng sinh tăng được Phúc
merit, only the merit from the Three Jewels
phần thì chỉ có công đức từ lơi tam bảo
can save them from suffering;
mới cứu được chúng sinh ra khỏi chỗ khổ
we cannot do that ourselves.
thôi chứ chúng ta không làm được điều đó
Do you understand, dear fellow practitioners? Therefore, do not be
đó quý đội Hữu rõ chưa Cho nên đừng ngã
arrogant or disrespectful. (Please
mạ làm gì tâm chếu hoàn quán xin đọc
continue reading.) Know that your rituals
tiếp biết rõ việc làm lễ của mình không
cannot be compared to those of the Sangha. The Sangha possesses the Six Harmonies, which
thể so sánh với chư Tăng Chư tăng có
is the Six Harmonies of
năng lực Lục Hòa là năng lực Lục Hòa của
single-minded practice towards Right View and
sự thực hành chuyên nhất đối với Chánh
Liberation through the complete eradication of
Kiến Giải Thoát qua sự viễn ni đoạn tận
desires. The Sangha also practices the Six Harmonies, and
các dục Chư tăng cũng thực hành Lục Hòa
we also practice the Six Harmonies, but the
chúng ta cũng thực hành Lục Hòa nhưng
merit of the Six Harmonies of the Sangha...  The practice of the Sangha is completely different
công đức Lục Hòa của Chư tăng khác hẳn
from the Six Harmonious Deeds of the esteemed lay Buddhists, do you
với công đức Lục Hòa của phật tử quý Đạ
understand? Because the Sangha practices
Hữu rõ chưa ạ vì Chư tăng thực hành
Right View and Liberation. The Sangha practices
chánh Kiến Giải Thoát Chư tăng thực hành
the methods of eradicating desires, while we
các pháp đoạn tận các dục còn chúng ta
are only lay practitioners. The
mới là tại gia cư sĩ
Sangha practices the Six Harmonious Deeds and Liberation,
tăng thực hành được Lục Hòa giải thoát
which is the liberation of precepts and the liberation of the
đó là giới giải thoát Kiến Giải Thoát
Sangha. While we lay
của Pháp Lục Hòa nhưng còn rất hạn chế
Buddhists have the capacity for the Six Harmonious Deeds, it is still very limited. The capacity for the Six Harmonious Deeds is
là năng lực Lục Hòa của phật tử còn hạn
limited because, in practicing Right View and Liberation, we still
chế Bởi sự thực hành chánh Kiến Giải
possess material possessions and family ties, so
Thoát phật tử còn sở hữu tài vật Quyến
we are still attached to the ego.
tức là chúng ta vẫn còn ái nhiễm vào cái
This is what we, esteemed fellow practitioners, are
ngã đây này các quý đạo hữu ạ
limited because of our
nhá còn hạn chế Bởi sự thực hành giới
practice of precepts. The monks practice the precepts of
ta của chúng ta là thực hành chánh kiến
liberation
các thầy là thực hành giới giải thoát
within the Six Harmonious Deeds, which include precepts and right view.
trong Lục Hòa có giới và chánh kiến nhá
They practice the liberation of intention,
thì các ngài ý hòa trong ý hòa giải
while we only practice the five
thoát còn chúng ta mới ý hòa bởi năm
precepts and eight precepts. And
giới tám giới Thôi các quý đạo hữu ạ và
our practices are only lay
các pháp của chúng ta mới là Pháp tại
Buddhist practices, not yet the true Dharma.  Because of
gia cư sĩ chứ chưa phải là Pháp của
the liberated one,
người giải thoát cho nên cái năng lực
our Six Harmonious Power is
Lục Hòa của chúng ta sinh ra nó có hạn
limited, dear fellow practitioners. It's
chế như vậy đấy các quý đạo hữu ạ Chứ
not like the Six Harmonious Power of
không phải được như năng lực Lục Hòa của
the venerable masters.
các quý thầy
Buddhists, please understand and remember mindfulness in
đâu phật tử hãy hiểu nhớ chánh niệm
respecting the Three Jewels and respecting the
trong niệm tôn kính tam bảo tôn kính
Sangha to preserve your own blessings.
chúng tăng để giữ gìn Phúc Báu cho chính
This is the end of the
mình đấy nhá thì đây là chúng ta đã hết
introductory part. Only by understanding the introductory part
phần lời dẫn để chúng ta có hiểu được
can we
lời dẫn thì chúng ta mới có thể thực
perform the rituals correctly. If we only
hành nghi lễ đúng được còn chúng ta chỉ
focus on the rituals and ignore the introductory part,
lấy phần nghi lễ mà bỏ qua phần lời dẫn
we are like a traveler
thì chúng ta giống như người đi đường
without direction. That is, the guide is not there to show
không có định hướng cái lời dẫn Tức là
us the way. In other words,
là người chỉ đường cho mình ấy mà tức là
we do all this within the Sangha's highest intention
chúng ta làm tất cả việc này trong cái
and
việc tăng Thượng chí tăng Thượng tâm và
with single-minded devotion, respectfully relying on the
trong cái niệm chuyên nhất cung kính
Three Jewels, dear fellow practitioners. In
nương tựa tam bảo các quý đạo hữu ạ trên
all rituals, we must
tất cả các khóa lễ chúng ta phải thực
practice with this mindset. Therefore, if you
hành trong cái tâm này Cho nên nếu các
give your Buddhist followers to
quý đạo hữu mà đưa cho Phật tử mình đi
perform a ceremony without letting them understand
làm lễ mà không cho Phật tử hiểu cái lời
this introductory part, then
dẫn này thì quả thật Phật tử đi trả được
how much merit and blessings will they receive? They will
cái công đức Phước báo là bao nhiêu
not attain enlightenment or accomplish anything. Do you
chẳng quán trí chẳng làm gì cả các quý
understand? Each one  Before performing the ceremony, we
đạo hữu rõ chưa Mỗi một lần đi làm lễ
must first meditate to increase our Supreme Will and
phải một lần quán chí để tăng Thượng chí
Supreme Mind.
lên tăng Thượng tâm lên các quý đầo Hữu
Do you understand, dear fellow practitioners? This will generate great blessings for us.
rõ chưa ạ đấ sinh ra phúc báo cho chúng
Moving on to the second part, the ritual of
bước sang phần thứ hai là phần nghi thức
offering the sacrifices, we must remember to
cúng lễ thì chúng ta nhớ là chúng ta
memorize and meditate fully
phải học đọc thuộc và quán trí đầy đủ
according to the instructions before
theo phần hướng dẫn đã rồi chúng ta mới
performing the ceremony. If we do not meditate
đi làm lễ còn chúng ta không quán trí
fully, either we
đầy đủ thì chúng ta hoặc đạo hữu nhắc
or our fellow practitioners should remind each other to meditate
mình hoặc mình nhắc Đạo Hữu để quán trí
fully before performing the ceremony. The ritual itself
đầy đủ rồi mới làm lễ nghi thức làm lễ
has two parts: firstly,
thì chúng ta có phần thứ nhất là hướng
instructions for the family to prepare the offerings, which you
dẫn gia đình sắm lễ thì các quý đạo hữu
will read in the ritual section. Regarding
sẽ đọc ở trong phần nghi
which ritual to use,
thức còn sử dụng Nghi thức nào thì đối
for a deceased Buddhist member of the
với người mất là người phật tử trong câu
Golden Chrysanthemum Club practicing the Six Harmonies, the
lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập tu Lộc Hòa thì các
Buddhist practitioners will use the ritual
phật tử sẽ dùng nghi thức là đạo tràng
performed by the congregation. For cases where the
đi làm phận sự đối với trường hợp người
deceased is a Buddhist member of the club, there are four
mất là phật tử câu lạc bộ có bốn chương
programs. When performing the ceremony, we will
trình Chúng ta đi làm lễ thì chúng ta sử
use two programs: one for a
dụng hai chương trình Một là chương
deceased member of the Golden Chrysanthemum Club
trình người mất Thuộc câu lạc bộ Cúc
practicing the Six Harmonies, and the
Vàng tập tu Lộc Hòa và chương trình thứ
second for a deceased member who is not a member of the
hai là người mất không thuộc câu lạc bộ
Golden Chrysanthemum Club practicing the Six Harmonies.  So,
Cúc Vàng tập tu lục hòa nhá Thế thì nếu
for the program where the deceased belongs to the
đối với chương trình mà người mất Thuộc
Golden Cup Club practicing the Six Harmonies,
câu lạc bộ cốc Vàng tập tu Lục Hòa thì
after we complete the seven-day memorial service,
sau khi chúng ta làm lễ Tuần thất xong
we guide the family to
thì chúng ta hướng dẫn cho gia đình tu
practice daily according to the program, which is the
tập hàng ngày theo cái chương trình là
daily practice for the 49-100 day memorial service
tu tập hàng ngày tuần thất 49 100 ngày
for
dành cho gia đình
that family. We will carefully read the title to
đấy chúng ta sẽ đọc kỹ tiêu đề để chúng
guide them. If
ta hướng dẫn còn trong 49 ngày Nếu đạo
our congregation performs daily ceremonies for the
tràng chúng ta đi làm lễ hàng ngày cho
deceased's family,
gia đình người mất ấy nếu chúng ch ta đi
we will use the "Bai" (offering) in
thì chúng ta sẽ dùng bài Bạch ở trong
this ceremony. This "Bai" and the daily
bài Lễ này nhá bài Bạch và chương trình
offering program will be used daily. When we perform daily ceremonies for the deceased and chant scriptures,
cúng lễ này hàng ngày đấy hàng ngày
we will use the exact
kinh hàng ngày thì chúng ta sẽ dùng đúng
words and rituals of this seven-day memorial service.
cái chứ cái nghi thức của tụng kinh tuần
Even if we perform the ceremony at night,
người mất ấy thì dù là cúng đêm đi chăng
we can still offer prayers to the Buddha.
nữa chúng ta vẫn bạch Phật được nha
We still offer prayers to the Buddha, directing our minds towards the
Chúng ta vẫn bạch Phật hướng tâm tới
Buddha so that we can offer prayers daily. When the
Phật để chúng ta bạch hằng ngày mà đạo
congregation comes to assist the deceased's family,
tràng đến trợ duyên cho gia đình người
we offer prayers to the Buddha according to the
mất thì chúng ta Bạch Cúng Phật theo cái
following "Bai" text, which means that the mind's contemplation
Văn Bạch sau tức là tâm chiếu Hoàn quán
will produce a "Bai" offering text.  We
sẽ đưa ra một cái Văn Bạch cúng phật và
offer prayers to Buddha and deities, and we still
cúng thần linh còn vong linh thì vẫn
offer prayers to the deceased as we do during the seven-day memorial service.
cúng như như cúng tuần thất các quý đạo
Have you understood, dear fellow practitioners? Then we move on to the
hữu rõ chưa ạ nha Rồi chúng ta đi đến
next part, which is chanting the bell, offering
phần tiếp theo là hô Chuông Nguyện
incense, and paying homage to Buddha. In this homage to Buddha,
Hương bạch Phật thì trong phần bạch Phật
the mind will
này tâm chiếu ho
guide you, dear fellow practitioners, to understand
quán hướng dẫn cho các quý đạo hữu rõ
this point during the seven-day memorial service. In
chỗ này ạ trong tuần thất đấy ạ Có cái
this part, the mind will read
phần này thì tâm chếu hoàn quán sẽ đọc
and analyze clearly in this prayer text
và phân tích rõ trong cái Văn Bạch này
so that we understand and have no
cho chúng ta hiểu sau này chúng ta không
questions later. After receiving
thắc mắc sau khi chúng ta tiếp nhận được
this program, we will review
chương trình này chúng ta sẽ xem lại cái
this video. Today is the
video này ạ Hôm nay là ngày tháng nă là
seventh day of the seventh month of the passing of a Buddhist devotee named [Name].
tuần thất thứ của đạo hữu phật tử tên Bỏ
On this day, month, and year, the burial or
báo thân vào ngày tháng năm an táng hoặc
cremation of remains is being performed at the
là cho ch cốt cửi tại đệ tử chúng con
home of the deceased Buddhist devotee. Following the request of the family, the assignment of the Dharma center, and the permission of the Sangha club, we, your disciples, have come to the family's home
chúng con tới gia chung của gia đình tín
at [address] to assist the
chủ tại địa chỉ để trợ duyên cho gia
family in cultivating merit, chanting scriptures, and offering prayers
đình tín chủ tu tập công đức tụng kinh
to dedicate blessings to the
cúng lễ để hồi hướng phước lành cho đạo
deceased Buddhist devotee, as we do not yet
tử đã bỏ báo th vì chúng con chưa biết
know the realm in which the deceased Buddhist devotee is
rõ đạo hữu phật tử sau khi bỏ báo thân
currently residing.  Therefore, in
hiện đang ở cảnh giới nào nên trong buổi
this ceremony, we respectfully request permission to refer to the
lễ này chúng con xin phép tùy duyên được
Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower as "Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist Follower" and respectfully
Hướng Tâm gọi là Linh thức Phật tử và
invite the Spiritual Consciousness of the
xin được dùng văn từ bạch nà bạch thỉnh
Buddhist follower to this Dharma
Linh thức Phật tử về trong pháp
assembly. Because we ourselves do not yet know
hội vì bản thân chúng ta chưa biết là
where our Buddhist followers will be reborn after leaving their physical bodies, the
sinh về đâu
above text, "Mindfulness and Contemplation,"
cho nên ở phần văn trên tâm chiếu Hoàn
says "We request to perform the memorial service for this
quán nói là xin làm tuần thuất cho đạo
Buddhist follower whose name is [name] who has left their
hữu phật tử tên là thế này đã bỏ báo
physical body, not yet called a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower."
thân chứ chưa gọi là Linh thức Phật tử
Only after requesting permission to call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower can we then call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower. Do you understand,
mà sau khi xin phép là được gọi là Linh
esteemed fellow practitioners?
gọi Linh thức Phật Tử có quý Đạ Hữu rõ
That is the correct terminology. We don't
không ạ Đấy gọi là chính ngữ đấy còn
know where they will be reborn, yet we call them a departed spirit or a spiritual Buddhist follower. That is incorrect. That's right, esteemed fellow practitioners, do you understand? Therefore, we must use the correct terminology. We don't know where they will be reborn, but now, in this ceremony, we respectfully
chưa biết người ta sinh về nơi đâu đã
call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the
gọi ta là vong linh đã gọi ta là linh
Buddhist follower. Even if they are reborn in heaven, it is appropriate to call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower. Do you understand,
Đức Phật tử thì cái đấy là không Đúng
esteemed fellow practitioners? Therefore,
rồi các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ Cho nên
we must use the correct terminology. "I
chúng ta phải dùng văn từ chuẩn nhá C
don't know where they will be reborn, but now,
không biết sinh về đây đâu nhưng bây giờ
I respectfully request permission in this ceremony to
con xin phép trong đàn lễ này chúng con
call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower." Even if they are reborn in
gọi Linh thức Phật tử thì dù sinh ở cõi
heaven, it is still appropriate to call them a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower.
trời cũng phù hợp với Linh thức Phật tử
Do you understand, esteemed fellow practitioners? No matter where they are reborn, we are
các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa ạ dù sinh ở đâu
called a Spiritual Consciousness of the Buddhist follower because
cũng gọi là Linh thức Phật tử Bởi Chúng
we are here with a spirit.  Listen up, esteemed fellow
ta ở trong này có linh thức đây này các
practitioners, is that clear?
quý Đạ Hữu rõ chưa nhá Thế còn gọi là
Regarding the third program, please allow me to
đối với chương trình thứ ba thì xin phép
call it "spirit of the deceased." That's
được gọi là vong linh Thì đấy là xin
just a request; everywhere people use the same term,
phép thôi thì ở đâu người ta cũng gọi là
like we give someone a
giống như mình đặt cho người ta một cái
name or designation. That's all.
danh từ danh xưng ấy nhá Thế thôi chứ
We're not going to accuse them of false speech or
chúng ta không móc vào tội vọng ngữ
deceitful language.
không móc vào tội vọng Ngữ
The mind is focused on the same point; I'm just reminding you, esteemed fellow
Nha thì tâm chếu hoàn quán chỉ nhắc các
practitioners, that it's different, and you might
quý đạo hữu ở chỗ này thôi nó khác và
not
quý đạo hữu chúng ta khi đọc vào không
understand why it's like that. To understand, you
thấy là tại sao lại như thế nhá để hiểu
should also explain this
và các quý đạo hữu cũng phải phân tích
clearly to your Buddhist followers before the
cho các phật tử của mình rõ trước khi đi
ceremony so they
làm lễ để cho các phật tử của mình
understand why it's called that.
à hiểu rõ là tại sao lại gọi như vậy và
In this section of the Prayer,
ở trong phần Văn Bạch này thì có phần là
if the family makes a donation to the Three Jewels to
nếu gia đình phát tâm cúng dường tam bảo
dedicate the merit to the deceased, the officiant will
hồi hướng phúc cho người mất thì chủ xám
guide the family representative to offer prayers. Respectfully,
hướng dẫn cho đại diện gia đình Bạch
esteemed fellow practitioners, in the
Kính thưa các quý đạo hữu trong các cái
seven-day memorial service, we have several
tuần thất thì chúng ta gồm có các cái
sutras. After reciting the sutras, the
bài kinh sau khi tụng bài kinh xong thì
officiant will give a Dharma discourse
chủ xám Khai Thị theo
according to the instructions in the sutra.
theo hướng dẫn trong bài kinh rồi cho
Therefore, it's very easy for us to
nên là rất dễ dàng cho việc chúng ta đi
perform the ceremony and very beneficial.  Dear fellow
làm lễ và rất lợi ích trong đàn lễ các
practitioners, we have a
quý đạo hữu ạ Có hẳn Văn Khai Thị h nii
very precious Dharma teaching. After the
rất là rất là quý Thế thì sau khi tâm
preparation and drafting are complete, we will present it to the
chế bản quán soạn xong sẽ là Bạch lên
monks for the master's approval
Chư tăng Để sư phụ chuẩn lại một lần nữa
before we release it. But for
rồi chúng ta mới phát hành nhưng hiện
now, we can use it temporarily.
tại bây giờ chúng ta có thể sử dụng tạm
Remember, dear fellow practitioners, is that clear?
được rồi nhớ Quý đầ Hữu rõ chưa ạ sử
Use it temporarily for the seven-week retreats to
dụng tạm để đi làm các tuần thất để có
benefit everyone.
lợi ích cho mọi người đã nhá
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
K
K
[Applause] [Music] [
[Vỗ tay]